<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A strange and horrible murther committed in White-Fryers upon Mr. John Blackston who was found murthered over against the Suger-Loafe, on the 7th of April, 1684.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1684</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 4 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 3 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A61739</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing S5817</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R221686</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99832960</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99832960</idno>
            <idno type="VID">37435</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A61739)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 37435)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 2154:11)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>A strange and horrible murther committed in White-Fryers upon Mr. John Blackston who was found murthered over against the Suger-Loafe, on the 7th of April, 1684.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet (2 p.)   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>printed by E. Mallet,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1684]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Imprint from colophon.</note>
                  <note>Print show-through.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the University of Illinois (Urbana-Champaign Campus). Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Blackston, John, d. 1684 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Murder --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2008-12</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-02</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-03</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-03</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:37435:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 4 -->
            <head>A Strange and Horrible MURTHER Committed in WHITE-FRYERS <hi>
                  <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>pon</hi> Mr. <hi>John Blackston,</hi> who was found Murthered over againſt the <hi>Suger-Loafe,</hi> on <date>the 7th of <hi>April,</hi> 1684.</date>
            </head>
            <p>Mr. <hi>JOhn Blackston,</hi> the unfortunate Subject of this Relation was a Gentleman of a good Family in the <hi>North of England,</hi> and Cozen to Capt. <hi>Blackston</hi> of the <hi>Temple,</hi> who dyed about three years ago. His great and familiar Acquaintance, with moſt Gentle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men of the Town rendered him publickly known, and e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>qually reſpected for a perſon of known Worth and un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>queſtionable Courage. The Watch going their Rounds in <hi>White-Fryers</hi> at one of the Clock on <hi>Tueſday</hi> Morning, found his Body lying in the Kennel near the <hi>Suger-Loafe</hi> in <hi>White-Fryers;</hi> Bleeding and lately Killed; upon which Notice being given to the Conſtable, he imediately or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dered it ſhould be removed, which was accordingly done, and carried into the <hi>Queens-Head Tavern</hi> where it lay till <hi>Wedneſday</hi> Night, and was then put into a Mourning Cof<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fen and carried to his own Lodgings, ſeveral Perſons Gentle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men and others, who were late out in publick Houſes, were ſecured and carriad to <hi>Bridewell,</hi> upon Suſpicion of being privy to the Murther; but the next day each perſon giving a fair Account of his Behaviour and Courſe of Life, They were all diſcharged by Sr. <hi>William Turner.</hi> The Gentleman by the freſhneſs of his Wounds, appeared to be lately killed, tho there was no perſon by, to give a parti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cular Account of it, only a Gentleman of the <hi>Temple,</hi> who was up at his Study, hearing a Noiſe in the Street, and
<pb n="1" facs="tcp:37435:2" rendition="simple:additions"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 5 -->
               <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
                  <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb n="2" facs="tcp:37435:3"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 6 -->the claſhing of Swords, look'd out of his Window, and ſaw three perſons fighting, of which the Gentleman now deceaſed was one. He had ſeveral Wounds in his left hand, through a Buſt Fringed Glove, and one mortal Wound on his right Side under the Ribs up into his Bo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dy and through his heart: the Orifice was very wide, and upon all Circumſtances, 'tis believed was foully done, &amp; that two perſons at the ſame time ſet upon him.</p>
            <p>The Coroner ſat upon the Body, and the Inqueſt found it wilfull Murther, for upon ſearching the Body<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> they found he had another Wound on his Back, which was a Stab after he fell. Several perſons were apprehended upon Suſpicion: but more particularly a Gentleman, who is ſup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſed one of the perſons who Killed him, is now taken &amp; committed to <hi>Newgate.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>The Diſcovery of this perſon was thus; that coming to a Chyrurgeon to be dreſt of a Wound he had upon his B<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>eaſt, he told him he had been lately in a Quarrel, had run his Adverſary through the Body, and cloſing with him ſhort<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ned his Sword, and ſtab'd him in the Back. The Chyrurgeon making this diſcovery upon the Report of Mr. <hi>Blackstons</hi> murther, the Gentleman was ſecured. The Gentleman of the <hi>Temple</hi> who look'd out his of Window called out to the Watch, but being late and no perſons in the Street, the mur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derers got off before they could be apprended. The Oc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>caſion of the Quarrel was about a Woman, whoſe Repu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tation has been blotted in the Eye of the World, which Mr. <hi>Blackston</hi> taking Notice of ſhe vow'd a Revenge, which ſhe thus contrived and effected as may be moſt reaſonably imagined. For Mr. <hi>Blackston</hi> being at a Tavern and en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quiring for ſome Gentlemen of his Acquaintance was di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rected up Stairs, where he found a Gentlewoman in com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pany with his Friends, and blaming them for admitting per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon ſo infamous in her Reputation turned her down Stair, whereupon ſhe ſaid he ſhould Repent that affront, and ſhe would have her ſatisfaction before many days paſt, which accordingly was done, by thoſe Ruffians, who thus Barbar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ouſly murthered him.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON</hi> Printed by <hi>E. Mallet,</hi> 1684.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
